[Music]
[Música]
Hello, how are you my dear
muy buenas qué tal estáis mis queridos
telesalseo lovers? Welcome once
amantes de telesalseo bienvenidos un día
again to my channel. I hope you're
más a mi canal Espero que estéis
enjoying your weekend. I'm here to
Disfrutando del fin de semana vengo a
bring you the latest information. I'm
traeros la última información que hay
going to react specifically to a thread
Voy a reaccionar en concreto a un hilo
by Axel. You already know that Axel is one
de Axel ya sabéis que Axel pues es uno
of the YouTubers that follows this topic.
de los youtubers que sigue en el tema él
Well, he has a different position than
bueno él tiene otra postura diferente a
ours because he defends that there could be a
la nuestra porque él defiende que podría
certain innocence on the part of
haber cierta inocencia por parte de
Daniel Sancho and he believes that there are strange things going on
Daniel Sancho y cree que hay cosas raras
behind the scenes. But opinions are respected
por detrás pero bueno se respetan las
as long as they don't cross
opiniones siempre y cuando no traspase
the line. But it's true that I'm going
el límite pero sí que es verdad que voy
to react to this thread that I
a reaccionar a este hilo que me he
found on Twitter because
encontrado en Twitter porque des me ha
several things have caught my attention and the
llamado la atención varias cosas y la
collection of information here is
recopilación de información que hay aquí
good for us to find out a
pues nos viene bien para enterarnos un
little about the latest. And this Monday
poco de lo último Y es que este lunes
the 13th, a couple of important things are happening.
día 13 pasan un par de cosas importantes
First of all, the most important thing is that Daniel Sancho will meet again with the judge. You already know that this was postponed, it was suspended due to the fact that Daniel demanded an interpreter, a translator into Spanish, in person and not by video call.
español en persona y no por videollamada
like the one who was eh on the 13th on Monday
como el que estaba eh el día 13 el lunes
Daniel will repeat the hearing
Daniel repetirá la vista pueden pasar
two things can happen either he pleads guilty
dos cosas que se declare culpable
recognizing the facts and then he is
reconociendo los hechos y entonces pues
directly sentenced and his
directamente se le condena y se le
sentence is reduced or he tries to plead
rebaja la pena o que intente declararse
innocent he pleads innocent and HM then there will have to
inocente se declare inocente y HM pues
be a trial and things get
haya que haber juicio y la cosa se
complicated he is going to try to plead
complique él va a intentar declararse
innocent he is going to try to fight for him for
inocente él va a intentar pelear por el
reckless homicide because that is what
por el homicidio imprudente porque es lo
his lawyer is recommending he already
que le está recomendando su abogado ya
said they intend to bring Daniel to
lo dijo ellos pretenden traer a Daniel
Spain in like 4at or 5 years and they
como dentro de 4at o 5 años a España y
would have to do this by getting
esto tendrían que hacerlo consiguiendo
reckless homicide which if I'm not
un homicidio imprudente que si no me
mistaken is 14 or 15 years in prison a
equivoco son 14 o 15 años de prisión un
third of or 5 years if he meets all the
tercio cu o 5 años si cumple todos los
requirements he can serve the rest of
requisitos puede cumplir el resto de de
the sentence in Spain with which we would be
la pena en España con lo que estaríamos
talking about that at 40 and a few years old
hablando de que con 40 y pocos años
Daniel would be on the street watch out eh watch
Daniel estaría en la calle ojo eh ojo
well eh the other thing that takes place on
bueno eh la otra cosa que tiene lugar el
Monday and they explained it in a
lunes y lo han explicado en una rueda de
press conference that they gave is that the lawyers
prensa que han dado es que los abogados
that Edwin's family has hired in
que ha contratado la familia de Edwin en
Spain well they are going to have a
España pues van a tener una reunión
important meeting with Edwin's family, not
importante con la familia de Edwin no
these lawyers because they were hired
estos abogados pues fueron contratados
to defend the honor based on what they
para defender el honor en base a lo que
saw was necessary of Edwin
vieran que fuera necesario de Edwin
Arrieta in Spain. We also have to talk
Arrieta en España Tenemos que hablar
about Daniel Sancho's forgiveness. Since it
también del perdón de Daniel Sancho Ya
seems that the family questions,
que parece que la familia reta duda eh
according to the lawyers, Ospina, that Daniel
según los abogados ospina de que Daniel
Sancho should ask for forgiveness, much less pay
Sancho pida perdón y mucho menos que
compensation. Daniel
abone una indemnización por el Daniel
Sancho, if he had wanted to ask for forgiveness, he has
Sancho si hubiera querido pedir perdón
already had time to do so and in
ya ha tenido tiempo para hacerlo y de
fact, what he is going to try to fight is that
hecho él lo que va a intentar pelear Es
he is a rape victim who
que él es una víctima de violación que
was defending himself. We already heard it
se estaba defendiendo ya lo escuchamos
the other day about the crime. They say that Juan
el otro día puesto crimen dicen que Juan
Gonzalo Espina explains that the family, uh,
Gonzalo espina explica que la familia eh
hired them to direct and coordinate
les contrató para dirigir y coordenar
the legal needs. They say that this is
las necesidades jurídicas dicen que esto
because the family had to hire them
porque la familia tuvo que contratar les
because this is because the family had to
porque esto es que la familia tuvo que
hire them because in Spain
contratarle porque en España se estaban
a lot of crazy things and a lot of
diciendo muchas locuras y muchas
barbarities were being said. And so, as if to put
barbaridades Y entonces como para poner
the brakes on a little bit, not in the face of certain
un poquito el freno no ante ciertas
barbarities that are being said,
barbaridades que se están diciendo se
things began to be said about Edwin, that if he
empezaron a decir cosas de Edwin que si
was a drug trafficker, that if he was from the
era un narcotraficante que si era de la
Colombian mafia, they said, let's go. eh
mafia colombiana se dijeron vamos eh
tremendous tremendous tremendous eh And the
tremendo tremendo tremendo eh Y la
Spanish press Well it was tremendous not
prensa española Pues fue tremenda no
to whitewash a little bit
para blanquear un poquito a
the family of Edw Arrieta had a
la familia de edw Arrieta tenía una cita
very important legal appointment for them
jurídica bastante importante para ellos
this coming Monday the 13th that morning in
este próximo lunes día 13 esa mañana en
which Daniel Sancho faces the
la que Daniel Sancho se enfrenta a la
reading of charges by the judge and
lectura de cargos por parte del juez y
the prosecutor of Thailand and they say that two
el fiscal de Tailandia y dicen que dos
things are that can happen he
cosas son las que pueden suceder que
admits the facts with which there would be no
admita los hechos con lo que no habría
trial and his sentence would
juicio y se reduciría su condena
probably be reduced to life imprisonment or that he
probablemente a cadena perpetua o que
denies them and we have to go to trial with
los niegue y haya que ir a juicio con
us on the program there you have the
nosotros en el programa ahí tenéis al
lawyer okay I think we can almost certainly
abogado vale yo creo que casi seguro
say that Daniel Sancho is not
podemos afirmar que Daniel Sancho no se
going to plead guilty and he is not going to
va a declarar culpable y no va a
admit to the facts García Montes has had
reconocer los hechos García Montes tiene
a clear strategy from the beginning and you
la estrategia clara desde el principio y
are juggling but Juano
estáis haciendo sus malabares pero Juano
let's go with that balance of the
vamos con ese balance de la rueda de
press conference because there is one thing that has
prensa porque hay una cosa que me ha
caught my attention in the event that
llamado mucho la atención en el caso de
Daniel Sancho's defense requests the
que pida la defensa de Daniel Sancho el
transfer to Spain they would try to oppose
traslado a España intentarían oponerse
we are very satisfied
nosotros nos mostramos muy satisfechos
with how the press conference has developed
de cómo se ha desarrollado la rueda de
especially that they have been able to
prensa sobre todo que se haya podido
coordinate this this press conference with Thailand
coordinar esta esta rueda con Tailandia
I think  that has been a success and with Colombia
creo que ha sido un éxito y con Colombia
at the same time, let's see, they are saying that
a la vez a ver está diciendo que
Edwin's family would try to oppose
intentarían oponerse la familia de Edwin
the transfer to Spain because they
al traslado a España porque ellos
want Edwin to Daniel to serve the
quieren que Edwin que Daniel cumpla la
full sentence in Thailand, but of course, I
pena completa en Tailandia pero claro yo
think that they have no decision there,
creo que ahí ya ellos no tienen decisión
okay. I think that based on whatever
vale Yo creo que ahí en base a lo que
the sentence is, the treaties that exist
sea la condena los tratados que hay
between countries are whatever they have. So
entre países son los que hayan Entonces
if Daniel gets it, I mean, if Daniel
si Daniel consigue O sea si Daniel
gets the reckless homicide and is
consigue el homicidio imprudente y es
sentenced to 15 years, what happens is that after
condenado a 15 años lo que hay es que a
5 years or a year at the latest. If he
los 5 años año como mucho tardar Si
meets all the requirements, the
cumple todos los requisitos salda la
compensation is paid and such, they
indemnización y tal lo tiene que se lo
have to grant it to him, okay, that's how it is.
tienen que conceder vale que eso es así
Now another thing is that it is a
Ahora otra cosa ya es que sea una cadena
life sentence or something like that, that will have to be
perpetua o algo por el estilo que ahí ya
discussed and there will be a conflict
habrá que discutirlo y habrá conflicto
regarding the issue of compensation that they
respecto al tema de la indemnización que
are saying that they believe Daniel
están diciendo que creen que Daniel no
will not want to pay it and so on, he may
va a querer pagarla y demás él podrá
want not to pay it, but if he wants to
querer no pagarla pero si se quiere
come to Spain and they put him on
venir a España y le ponen una
compensation, Edwin's family
indemnización que la familia de Edwin
would try to fight for the maximum, eh,
iba a intentar pelear por la máxima eh
one of the requirements, if I'm not mistaken,
uno de los requisitos si no me equivoco
after that third of serving the
después de ese tercio de cumplir la
sentence in Thailand, another of the
condena en Tailandia otro de los
requirements  is to settle the civil matter, the
requisitos es saldar el tema civil la
compensation that there is. Then he is going to have to
indemnización que haya Entonces lo va a
pay it whether he wants to
tener que pagar si sí o sí o sea quiera
or not. You'll be able to answer
o no quiera vez poder responder a las
questions live from all the media
preguntas en directo de todos los medios
that have come. I think it's a very
que han acudido creo que es algo muy
positive thing to show transparency, eh,
positivo para mostrar transparencia eh
which is what the families are looking for
que es lo que las familias buscando
closeness and humanity on your part in
cercanía y humanidad por su parte en
relation to the question that was raised, eh,
relación a la pregunta que planteaba eh
the family will assess at the
la familia va a valorar en su momento
appropriate time, assuming that there is a
oportuno suponiendo que exista una
conviction, and assuming that this is a
condena y suponiendo que esta sea una
life sentence and that
condena a cadena perpetua y que
Mr. Sancho subsequently requests to
posteriormente señor Sancho solicite
come to Spain to serve his sentence. The
venir a cumplir la pena a España la
family will assess whether there has
familia valorará si ha existido
really been a will to forgive or to
realmente voluntad de perdón o de
compensate for the damage caused in order to
resarcimiento del daño producido para
make a decision that. Possibly it is
tomar una decisión que Posiblemente sea
the opposition to this request to
la oposición a esta solicitud de
comply with the. Well, they will
cumplimiento de la bueno ellos se se
want to oppose it, but I don't know to what
querrán oponer pero no sé hasta qué
extent they have the option to give their opinion. I don't
punto tienen ahí opción de de opinar No
know, eh, I don't know. They communicate from
lo sé eh lo desconozco comunican desde
Bangkok the difficulty of having a
Bangkok la dificultad de tener un
Spanish translator in the Daniel
traductor a español en el caso Daniel
Sancho case, but Thailand signed the
Sancho pero Tailandia firmó el tratado
international human rights treaty. So
de derechos internacional Así que lo
today, Friday, November 10, there have
asigna hoy viernes 10 de noviembre han
been news regarding the
salido novedades en cuanto al caso de
Daniel Sancho case from the F agency in
Daniel Sancho desde la agencia F desde
Bangkok 10  November the news came out today
Bangkok 10 de noviembre ha salido hoy la
about the difficulty of having a
noticia de la dificultad de tener un
good interpreter in a
buen intérprete en un tribunal
Thai court and of course today there was also
thailandés y por supuesto hoy también ha
a press conference by Juan gos
habido una rueda de prensa de Juan gos
Pina regarding the legal representation
Pina en cuanto a la representación legal
that will defend the interests of the
que defenderá los intereses de la
Arrieta family. But according to what we're told
familia Arrieta Pero según nos cuentan
from Bangkok, having a good
desde Bangkok contar con un buen
interpreter from Thai to Spanish
intérprete del tailandés al español que
is not an easy task in the courts
no es una tarea fácil en los tribunales
of Thailand. This is something that
de Tailandia Esto es algo que solicita
Daniel Sancho is requesting and they have to have it, it's their
Daniel Sancho que lo tienen que tener es
right, it's Daniel's right and they
el derecho es el derecho de Daniel y lo
have to have it, so for whatever reason,
tienen que tener así que por lo que sea
if they haven't got it by tomorrow, by Monday,
si para mañana para el lunes no lo han
tomorrow it won't have happened. If they
conseguido mañana no ha pasado si no lo
haven't got it, they have to
han conseguido tienen que volver a
postpone it again, well, I don't rule it out. eh family,
aplazarlo pues no lo descarto eh familia
that it will be postponed. Next Monday,
que se aplace el próximo lunes
a pre-trial hearing will appear for
comparecerá una vista previa al juicio
the murder of the Colombian Edgun
por el crimen del colombiano edgun
Arrieta in southern Thailand. But
Arrieta en el sur de Tailandia Pero
according to Thai law, the court is
según la ley tailandesa el tribunal está
obliged to provide an interpreter to the
obligado a proveer de un intérprete al
accused during the investigation, even
acusado durante la investigación aún así
the preliminary hearings and the trial, and
las vistas preliminares y el juicio y
Sancho has already requested one in Spanish, but
Sancho ya ha pedido uno en español pero
legal experts and interpreters assure
expertos legales y intérpretes aseguran
that it is not easy to find
que no es nada fácil encontrar a
professionals versed in the
profesionales versados en el lenguaje
legal language at the hearing.  on Monday on the
jurídico en la vista del lunes en la
island of Samui Sancho son of actor
isla de samui Sancho hijo del actor
Rodolfo Sancho and grandson of Sancho Gracia
Rodolfo Sancho y Nieto de Sancho gracia
as we know must plead guilty
como sabemos deberá declararse culpable
or innocent to the charges brought by the
o Inocente de los cargos que presente el
prosecutor which would include
fiscal que incluirían el crimen con
premeditated murder and concealment of the body on
premeditación y ocultación del cuerpo el
October 26 this hearing was
pasado 26 de octubre esta vista quedó
postponed due to Sancho's request for
aplazada por la petición de Sancho de
a Spanish interpreter after
tener un intérprete al español después
having testified so far both
de haber declarado hasta ahora tanto
before the police and the judge always in
ante la policía como al juez siempre en
English what happens is that the
inglés lo que pasa es que los tribunales
Thai courts are obliged to find an
tailandeses están obligados a buscar un
interpreter in the language of the accused if
intérprete en el idioma del acusado si
requested as established by their
este lo pide ya que así lo establece su
legal code and the international covenant
código jurídico y el pacto internacional
on civil and political rights signed
de derechos civiles y políticos firmado
by Thailand
por Tailandia
and Well no matter how complicated it is they have to
e Pues por muy complicado que sea es que
have it eh I mean it's
lo tienen que tener eh o sea es que es
a right they are going to
un derecho es que lo van lo van a volver
postpone it again if not well here Now speak
a aplazar si no bueno aquí Habla ahora
in this next clip of the 20
en este siguiente clip de los 20
witnesses that the Thai police already
testigos que la policía tailandesa ya
had at the beginning of the investigation this
tenía al inicio de la investigación esto
to make it clear that the police
para que que quede claro que la policía
already when the case went viral we
ya cuando el caso ya se hizo viral esto
have talked about this on many occasions they already
lo hemos hablado en muchas ocasiones ya
had it more than tied up or rather  Look
lo tenían más que atado o sea fijaros
at how much they had tied up, not
Hasta qué punto tenían atado ya no
only the cameras, which is what
solamente las cámaras que es lo que
we saw, but witnesses and everything. I
hemos visto sino testigos y de todo o
mean, this has been a case that is
sea es que esto ha sido un caso que es
very clear and in a bottle. Okay, here you
como muy blanco y en botella vale aquí
have like that page of the
tenéis como esa página de del dossier
police dossier in which they put 20 witnesses
policial en el que metían 20 testigos
there, which are 20 witnesses in the
ahí que son 20 testigos en la zona
tourist area of ​​Copan Gang. eh, the first ones
turística de copan Gang eh los primeros
say that they are the drivers of two
dicen que son los conductores de dos
garbage trucks, the
camiones de basura del recolector de
garbage collector, the garbage sorter that
basura el clasificador de basura que
found eh body parts, eh, an
encontró eh partes del cuerpo eh una
employee of the Big th supermarket,
empleada de la tienda Big th supermarket
another employee of the eh Lim Pong store,
otro empleado de la tienda eh lim p pong
which is the Hmart, which would be like the
que es el el hmart que sería como la la
hardware store. In this case, they sell
ferretería en este caso venda venta de
equipment used for cutting
equipos utilizados para el corte de del
bodies. Also, employees of the
cuerpo también empleados de de la
Pang Wiang school, employees of the
escuela pang wiang empleados de la
Anantara school, and employees of the
escuela anantara y empleados de la
Bo en Yen school. Well, as for the
escuela Bo en yen bueno en cuanto a la
translation, I mean that it refers
traducción yo me refiero que se refiere
to employees of the Piman Hotel, employees
a empleados del Hotel piman empleados
of the eh Anantara hotel, and then the thing about
del eh hotel anantara y después lo de
Bo en Yen employees, I think or I
empleados de Bo en yen yo me parece o
suppose it will be the Bugin, not the Bugay
Supongo que será el bugin no el bugay
Villas. I suppose, let's suppose that  It will be eh
Villas Supongo vamos Supongo que será eh
the employee of the buggy no, the one that
la empleada del bugay no la je que que
appeared not on Antena 3 eh speaking there in
salió no en Antena 3 eh hablando ahí en
that interview on camera I suppose it will be
esa entrevista en cámara Yo supongo que
eh it is also expanded Noa later We
será eh es amplada también Noa después
also have eh the people or the
También tenemos eh las personas que o la
person who rented that motorcycle and
persona que le alquiló esa motocicleta y
the person who rented eh the kayak
la persona que le alquiló eh los kayak
well the kayak was sold to him no I mean if he
bueno el kayak se lo vendió no O sea si
gave her 1000 bucks I think that is
le dio 1000 pavos yo creo que que eso es
a purchase I don't know if that is a rental
una compra no sé si eso es un alquil
1000 bucks which in this case would be
1000 pavos que en este caso serían
several no because on that time on that
varias no porque en esa vez en esa
supposed time that Daniel Sancho went to
supuesta vez que fue Daniel sancho a
rent the kayak well there were several
alquilar el kaya pues había varias
people no then they also put like
personas no después también ponen como
with an asterisk the people who
con asterisco las personas que
found the bodies in the sea in
encontraron los cuerpos en el mar en
salad Beach And finally they place here a
salad Beach Y por último colocan aquí un
doctor who participated in the autopsy these
médico que participó en la autopsia esto
were the 20 witnesses that were placed in the
eran los 20 testigos que colocaban en el
police dossier Here I am counting
dossier policial Aquí yo estoy contando
a two well from the autopsy I don't know if it is
un dos bueno de la autopsia no sé si es
a witness that they could have before
un testigo que pudieran tener antes de
closing the investigation family What do
cerrar la investigación familia Qué
you think what do you think will happen on
pensáis ustedes qué creéis que pasará el
Monday important what do you think will happen
lunes importante qué creéis que pasará
on Monday  Whatever happens, we will be
el lunes lo que sea que pase estaremos
here informing you. I send you a big kiss
por aquí informando os mando un beso muy
and until the next video. Bye
fuerte y hasta el siguiente vídeo chao
[Music]
[Música]
Bye
chao